YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 10. Audiovisual Materials
Sophia Smith Collection
YWCA of the U.S.A. Record. Record Group 10. Audiovisual Materials
1963-2001
Young Women's Christian Association of the U.S.A.
324_rg10
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
This Record Group forms part of the YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. It includes professionally produced video and audio recordings of program materials, public service announcements, and training materials; audio soundtracks for slideshows. There are also in-house recordings of speeches, lectures, and panels; programs at local, regional, national, and World YWCA events, such as conferences and conventions; staff meetings; teleconferences; some YWCA-themed music; and a few interviews and oral histories. Topics include racism, child care, financial development and health.
Forms part of the YWCA of the U.S.A. Records.
This record group includes professionally produced video and audio recordings of program materials, public service announcements, and training materials; audio soundtracks for slideshows. There are also in-house recordings of speeches, lectures, and panels; programs at local, regional, national, and World YWCA events, such as conferences and conventions; staff meetings; teleconferences; some YWCA-themed music; and a few interviews and oral histories. Topics include racism, child care, financial development and health.
NOTE: Original audio-visual materials are closed to research. In some cases, use copies are available. These are marked with an asterisk [*]. Researchers interested in accessing audio-visual materials for which there is no extant use copy should contact the Sophia Smith Collection to discuss options.
This record group is divided into two Series:
I. AUDIO
II. VIDEO
The records are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection without any additional restrictions. Original format records are stored off-site and researchers must give SSC staff two working days (Monday - Friday) advance notice for retrieval. Advanced notice is not required to view microfilmed records in the Sophia Smith Collection.
Access to audiovisual materials may first require production of research copies.
Additional Formats
A copy of the microfilmed records of the YWCA of the U.S.A. Records is available to borrow from the William Allan Neilson Library at Smith College via Interlibrary Loan.
To request the microfilm from our library you will need to submit the following information to your library's Interlibrary Loan department:
Author: Young Women's Christian Association of the U.S.A. National Board
Title: Records, 1876-1970 [microform]
WorldCat Accession Number: OCLC 57415795
Notes: "Call # 689" and reel number(s) you want to borrow
Full descriptions and reel lists of the microfilm are available online.
The YWCA of the U.S.A. donated a portion of its records to the Sophia Smith Collection in 1964 and the remainder in 2002 and 2003.
Record Groups
The YWCA of the USA Records are arranged as follows:
YWCA of the U.S.A. Records (main record)
RECORD GROUP 1. GENERAL AND HISTORY
RECORD GROUP 2. PREDECESSOR ORGANIZATIONS AND NATIONAL BOARD
RECORD GROUP 3. NATIONAL ADMINISTRATIVE OFFICE
RECORD GROUP 4. NATIONAL CONVENTIONS AND CONFERENCES
RECORD GROUP 5. INTERNATIONAL WORK
RECORD GROUP 6. PROGRAM
RECORD GROUP 7. STUDENT WORK
RECORD GROUP 8. COMMUNITY ASSOCIATIONS
RECORD GROUP 9. PHOTOGRAPHS
RECORD GROUP 10. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS
Artifacts
The Microfilmed Records
The Oversized Materials
This Record group forms part of the YWCA of the U.S.A. Records
Series Descriptions
- SERIES I. AUDIO
  The audio materials consist 1.75 linear feet of audiocassettes, reel-to-reel tapes, 33 1/3 and 78 rpm discs, and related print material, 1963-2000, n.d.. They are arranged by format and then chronologically. They include professionally produced soundtracks for slideshows, scripted presentations to accompany training materials, and YWCA public service announcements. There are also in-house recordings of staff meetings; programs at local, regional, national, and World YWCA events, such as conferences and conventions; and some YWCA-themed music. Topics include racism, child care, financial development and health.
  USE COPIES: Only those items with Use Copies (selected items in box 1062 and all of box 1066) can be accessed immediately. Consult with Sophia Smith Collection staff about options for obtaining Use Copies of other items.
- SERIES II. VIDEO
  This series consists of 56.5 linear feet of videotapes in VHS, Beta, and Umatic formats with a small amount of accompanying print records, 1974-2001, n.d. (bulk 1985-96). They are arranged chronologically with undated and unidentified tapes at the end.
  Included are professionally produced program materials, public service announcements, and training materials. There are also in-house recordings of staff meetings, teleconferences, events, Conventions, conferences, and councils, speeches, lectures, and panels. Included are a few interviews and oral histories as well as local television news coverage of YWCA events, mostly from the 1990s.
  In keeping with its long history of adaptation of techniques to suit the times, the National Association made extensive use of video for Convention preparation, program, and training materials in the 1980s and 1990s. This is particularly the case for the years (1983-circa 2000) that the National Association owned the Leadership Development Center in Phoenix, Arizona. That facility was designed with extensive video production in mind. Included among these videos are presentations related to re-examinations of the YWCA's Purpose statement, progress reports on the legal action brought by the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission related to the YWCA employment policies, and videotaped tributes to outgoing YWCA officers prepared for Conventions.
  USE COPIES: Only those videotapes with existing Use Copies, (stored in boxes 1111 and 1112) are available for viewing immediately. Researchers should consult with Sophia Smith Collection staff about the options for access to the other videos.
- SERIES I. AUDIO MATERIALS
  [* indicates Use Copy available]
  - Written material re audio, 1967-81, n.d. (Box 1062, Folder 1)
  - Reel-to-reel tapes (16 mm)-Originals DO NOT USE
    - "Work-Not Luck," "Loneliness," and "Learning," three 30 second Radio Public Service announcements featuring Lucille Ball, n.d. (Box 1062, Folder 2)
    - YWCA Radio Public Service Announcement, Nov 1994, [may be "Join Us" in audiocassettes below] (Box 1062, Folder 3)
  - Discs (78 rpm)-Original DO NOT USE
    - "Our Song" recorded by Detroit Y-Teens, circa 1948 (Box 1062, Folder 4)
  - LP Discs (33 1/3 rpm)-Originals DO NOT USE, [Use copies at rear of box]
    - The March on Washington, August 28, 1963: We Shall Overcome, Authorized recording produced by the Council for United Civil Rights Leadership, 1963 * (Box 1062, Folder 5)
    - Contemporary Programming Series Kit No. 2: "Money Talk: The Wise Consumer Kit," presented by Dr. Aurelia Toyer, circa 1967 *, [See also Supplementary material below and in Record Group 6. Series II. Training and Personnel] (Box 1062, Folder 6)
    - "Discover You with Us: Becoming a Professional Person," Presented by Daphne Hughes and Joann Thompson, YWCA Bureau of Personnel and Training, 1968 (Box 1062, Folder 7)
    - It's Not Where You've Been, It's Where You're Going, Going, Going-Join the YWCA," music by Mundell Lowe, lyrics by Kurt Lassen, March 1970 *, [See also Supplementary material] (Box 1062, Folder 8)
    - "The Y's Kids Sing it Loud," Santa Ana YWCA, circa 1970 (Box 1062, Folder 9)
    - Contemporary Program Kit-No. 4, "The YWCA Purpose: An Action Agenda," compiled by Frances Helen Mains, n.d. *, [see also Record Group 6. Series II. Training and Personnel] (Box 1062, Folder 10)
  - LP Discs--USE COPIES
    - The March on Washington, August 28, 1963: We Shall Overcome, Authorized recording produced by the Council for United Civil Rights Leadership, 1963 (Box 1062, Folder 5)
    - Contemporary Programming Series Kit No. 2: "Money Talk: The Wise Consumer Kit," presented by Dr. Aurelia Toyer, circa 1967 (Box 1062, Folder 6)
    - It's Not Where You've Been, It's Where You're Going, Going, Going-Join the YWCA," music by Mundell Lowe, lyrics by Kurt Lassen, March 1970 (Box 1062, Folder 8)
    - Contemporary Program Kit-No. 4, "The YWCA Purpose: An Action Agenda," compiled by Frances Helen Mains, n.d. (Box 1062, Folder 10)
  - Audiocassettes-Originals DO NOT USE, [see box 1066 for Use Copies]
    - Convention
      - 27th 1976: slide story, "Freedom to Be…Power to Move" *, [See also Record Group 9. Series II. Slides] (Box 1063, Folder 1)
      - 1989: Plenary Session II-Part I and Part II, Zimmerman, Putnam, Norwood, Stanley, Keene, Saturday, 7 Jan 1989, 1:30-3:30 pm (Box 1063, Folder 2-3)
      - Convention Committee, 17 November 1995 (Box 1063, Folder 4)
    - Conference: Wingspread Conference, co-sponsored by the Johnson Foundation and the YWCA Center for Racial Justice, "Eliminating Racism: Building on the YWCA Experience," Racine Wisconsin, Jun 1977. Tapes are R-409 and R-410, "Conversations from Wingspread: Racial Justice and the Urban Crisis" * (Box 1063, Folder 5-6)
    - National Board and National Administrative Office
      - National Board Meeting with Prema Mathai-Davis, #5-8, circa 1990s (Box 1063, Folder 7-10)
      - YWCA Strategic Plan, Jul 1995 * (Box 1063, Folder 11)
      - Meeting of National Staff re possibility of selling 600 Lexington Ave., 28 Apr 1981* (Box 1063, Folder 12)
      - National Staff Retreat, Sep1988
        - Opening address by Gwendolyn C. Baker, 13 Sep (Box 1063, Folder 13)
        - Closing address by Gwendolyn C. Baker, 17 Sep (Box 1063, Folder 14)
      - Finance and Development
        - Gwendolyn Baker, National Support Plan [included in the National Support Kit,1987], Sep 1986 * (Box 1063, Folder 15)
        - Changes in the YWCA Retirement Fund, Inc., n.d. (Box 1063, Folder 16)
        - "Funding Tape," 10/8/84, "Latch Key Program," etc. [probably Fund for the Future] (Box 1063, Folder 17)
        - Mike Murphy on fundraising, circa 1980s (Box 1063, Folder 18)
        - Millennium 2000 Campaign
          - Meeting, 27 June [circa 1998] (Box 1064, Folder 1)
          - Genesis Group, 30 October 1998 (Box 1064, Folder 2-3)
        - World Service Council
          - Program [Area Meeting?] Detroit, 13 Apr 1977
            - Lee, Rockefeller, Claytor, Smith, Johnson (Box 1064, Folder 4)
            - Christine Navet (Box 1064, Folder 5)
          - Annual Meeting, 26 October 1993 (Box 1064, Folder 6-7)
          - 1998
            - Tape # 14 and #15 (Box 1064, Folder 8-9)
            - Annual Meeting, 9 Oct 1998 (Box 1064, Folder 10-11)
            - Executive Committee, 8 Oct 1998 (Box 1064, Folder 12-13)
          - Annual Meeting, 5 Oct 2000 (Box 1064, Folder 14)
          - Executive Committee Meeting, 4 Oct 2000 (Box 1064, Folder 15-16)
      - Publicity
        - "It Takes All Kinds... to Make a World," audio for slide presentation, 1980, [see also Record Group 9. Series II. Slides] (Box 1064, Folder 17)
        - "Shape Up," 60 second radio public service announcement, Nov 1994 (Box 1064, Folder 18)
        - "Join Us," 60 second radio public service announcement produced by Phyllis Kerlin and Associates, n.d. * (Box 1064, Folder 19)
    - International Work
      - Breaking Barriers-Short Version, "The YWCA-A World of Women," audio for slide presentation, Nov 1982, [See also Record Group 9. Series II. Slides] (Box 1065, Folder 1)
      - Breaking Barriers-Full Version, "International Study Program-Asian Focus," audio for slide presentation, Nov 1982, [See also Record Group 9. Series II. Slides] (Box 1065, Folder 2)
    - Program
      - "The Program Planning Process" with Helen Southard. Included in "A Handbook for New Administrative Volunteers," 1981, [see also Record Group 6. Series II. Training and Personnel] (Box 1065, Folder 3)
      - Teen Age and Younger Girls
        - National Teen Organization, Central Region Assembly, 1977 (Box 1065, Folder 4)
        - National Teen Organization, Central Region, "Poetry on Racism," 1977 or 1997(?) (Box 1065, Folder 5)
        - National Teen Organization, Eastern Region, n.d. (Box 1065, Folder 6)
      - U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development speaker on "Transitional Housing," 1989 * (Box 1065, Folder 7)
    - Student Work
      - National Student Assembly of the YWCA (NSAY)
        - Opening session, 18 Mar 1985 (Box 1065, Folder 8)
        - 1996 (Box 1065, Folder 9)
      - National Student Council at UCLA, Apr 1986
        - 5 Apr, #5 and #6 also 8-24-84 (Box 1065, Folder 10)
        - 5 Apr, #3 and #4 (Box 1065, Folder 11)
        - 6 Apr, #1 and #2 (Box 1065, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Song about the YWCA by Angelina [Marcatos?], n.d. (Box 1065, Folder 13)
      - "Touching the Rock," written by Tina Davidson for the New Castle County, Delaware, YWCA Centennial, circa 1995 (Box 1065, Folder 14)
      - YWCA Vocal and instrumental by Diane Zucker, HR(?) YWCA, n.d. ["It's a new dawn of a new day at the YWCA"] (Box 1065, Folder 15)
  - Audiocassettes--USE COPIES (Box 1066)
    - From box 1063 folder 1 - Convention: 27th, 1976 slide story, "Freedom to Be... Power to Move" (Box 1066)
    - From box 1063 folder 5; box 1063 folder 6 - Conference: Wingspread Conference, co-sponsored by the Johnson Foundation and the YWCA Center for Racial Justice, "Eliminating Racism: Building on the YWCA Experience," Racine Wisconsin, Jun 1977. Tapes are R-409 and R-410, "Conversations from Wingspread: Racial Justice and the Urban Crisis" (Box 1066)
    - From box 1063 folder 11 - YWCA Strategic Plan, Jul 1995 (Box 1066)
    - From box 1063 folder 12 - Meeting of National Staff re possibility of selling 600 Lexington Ave., 28 Apr 1981 (Box 1066)
    - From box 1063 folder 15 - Gwendolyn Baker, National Support Plan [included in the National Support Kit,1987], Sep 1986 (Box 1066)
    - From box 1064 folder 19 - "Join Us," 60 second radio public service announcement produced by Phyllis Kerlin and Associates, n.d. (Box 1066)
    - From box 1065 folder 7 - U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development speaker on "Transitional Housing," 1989 (Box 1066)
- SERIES II. VIDEOTAPES
  - Written material
    - General, 1977-2001, n.d. (Box 1067, Folder 1-2)
    - Leadership Development Center video library, 1997-98, n.d. (Box 1067, Folder 3)
    - "It's Okay to Say No Way!": publicity and leaders' guide, 1986 (Box 1067, Folder 4)
    - National Support videotape: correspondence and leaders' guide, 1986-87 (Box 1067, Folder 5)
    - Purpose Study Committee Panel Presentation: script and leaders' guide, 1989-90 (Box 1067, Folder 6)
  - Videotapes-Originals DO NOT USE, [see boxes 1111 and 1112 for Use Copies]
    - 1970s and National Conference: "MC Narrator," Umatic, circa 1970s (Box 1068, Folder 1)
    - "Consultation on Job Market and Career Development for Teen Women," Umatic, 1974 (Box 1068, Folder 2)
    - "National YWCA Dialogue" (Role-playing situations at Learning Center,) Umatic, 1974 (Box 1068, Folder 3)
    - Faces of Racism, VHS, 1975 * (Box 1068, Folder 4)
    - Understanding Institutional Racism, VHS, 1977 * (Box 1068, Folder 5)
    - Stained Glass Window Dedication, VHS, 1977 (Box 1068, Folder 6)
    - From Racism to Pluralism, VHS, 1978 * (Box 1068, Folder 7)
    - YWCA of the USA: Walk for the ERA, San Diego, CA, 15 Nov 1981
      - Original footage (2 tapes), Umatic (Box 1068, Folder 8-9)
      - Edited Master, Umatic (2) (Box 1068, Folder 10)
      - Edited Version, VHS (Box 1068, Folder 11)
      - Edited Version, Beta (Box 1068, Folder 12)
    - YWCA, Sara-Alyce Wright, VHS, 11 Feb 1982 (Box 1068, Folder 13)
    - Public Service Announcements featuring Lucille Ball, "YW Today," Umatic, 26 Aug 1982 (Box 1068, Folder 14)
    - Jewell Graham Stewardship Speech, VHS, 1983 (Box 1068, Folder 15)
    - 30 Second Action Spots: "Job Skills," "Getting Involved," "Getting Your Act Together," produced by Linc, Inc., Umatic, VHS, 1983 (Box 1068, Folder 16-17)
    - Public Service Announcements featuring Lucille Ball, "Working," "Loneliness," and "Learning," VHS, 1983 * (Box 1068, Folder 18)
    - Jewel Freeman Graham Interview, VHS, circa 1983 (Box 1068, Folder 19)
    - Jewel Graham Interview, Lucille Ball Spots, and Action Spots, 1983, Umatic, and VHS * (Box 1068, Folder 20)
    - Learning Center Outside Group Shot, Phoenix, AZ, Umatic, Oct 1983 (Box 1069, Folder 1)
    - Interview with Joyce Jaynes, National Board YWCA, KAET-TV, AZ, Umatic, 12 Oct 1983 (Box 1069, Folder 2)
    - Leadership Development Center Dedication Program, 16 Oct 1983
      - Edited Video segment used during Dedication Program, Umatic (Box 1069, Folder 3)
      - Leadership Development Center Dedication Program, Umatic, VHS (Box 1069, Folder 4-5)
    - Role-Playing Situation, Financial Development Workshop, LDC, Umatic, Oct 1983 (Box 1069, Folder 6)
    - "History... in the Company of Women," produced by World Communications, Inc., 1983-84
      - Studio taping #1, Mary Ann Lundy, Masequa Myers, Umatic, 1984 (Box 1069, Folder 7)
      - Studio taping # 3: Georgia Alverez, Evelina Antonetti, Umatic, 1984 (Box 1069, Folder 8)
      - "Cut down version," Umatic, 27 Jan 1984 (Box 1069, Folder 9)
      - Unmarked Umatic (Box 1069, Folder 10)
      - YWCA Version, Umatic (Box 1069, Folder 11)
      - New Edit, Umatic (Box 1069, Folder 12)
      - Master, VHS (Box 1069, Folder 13)
    - Phyllis Chesler, "How Power and Violence Relate to the Oppression of Women," LDC, Umatic, 7 Apr 1984 (Box 1069, Folder 14)
    - National Conference for YWCA Program staff keynote address by Dorothy Height, 3 May 1984 (Box 1069, Folder 15)
    - Joyce Jaynes, Edited for National Board Meeting, Umatic, 15 May 1984 (Box 1069, Folder 16)
    - Glendale, California, YWCA support tape, VHS, 31 Aug 1984 (Box 1069, Folder 17)
    - "YWCA 2000 A.D." and 3 Lucille Ball TV Spots, produced by Linc, Inc., VHS, Sep 1984 * (Box 1069, Folder 18)
    - Panel Discussion: Joyce Gillian Goldberg, Moderator: Dorothy Hopkins, Grenada; Nancy Marant, Fort Worth; Jin Yng Kim, Korea, Umatic, 26 Oct 1984 (Box 1070, Folder 1)
    - Panel Discussion, Elimination of Racism, Tape II, LDC, Umatic, 1984 (Box 1070, Folder 2)
    - Multi-Cultural Festival, LDC Production, Umatic, Oct 1984 (Box 1070, Folder 3)
    - Y'all Come Western Night, LDC, VHS, 1 Oct 1984 (Box 1070, Folder 4)
    - Convention Cycle Meeting with Glendora Putnam, Umatic, 1985 (Box 1070, Folder 5)
    - "New Tales from the South Pacific," World YWCA promotional video re Youth Development in the South Pacific, VHS, 1985 (Box 1070, Folder 6)
    - Phumzile Mlambo, Umatic, 1985 (Box 1070, Folder 7)
    - Triple Jeopardy, LDC, VHS, 1985 (Box 1070, Folder 8)
    - Action Series II, 30 second spots produced by Linc, Inc. "Fitness," "YW Women" and "Network," Umatic, VHS, 1985 (Box 1070, Folder 9-10)
    - "Salute to the Volunteer," 95th Tournament of Roses Parade and YWCA 125th Birthday, Umatic, VHS, 1985 (Box 1070, Folder 11-12)
    - Orientation: YWCA Mission, Basic Board Orientation, Staff/Volunteer Relationship, Strategic Planning, Financial Development, VHS, 1985 (Box 1070, Folder 13)
    - Middle East Encounter, VHS, 1985 * (Box 1070, Folder 14)
    - Women Candidates in the Age of Television, VHS, 1985 (Box 1070, Folder 15)
    - Career Volunteer Development Project/Corporate Responsibility, VHS, 1985 (Box 1070, Folder 16)
    - Career Volunteer Development Project, VHS, 1985 * (Box 1070, Folder 17)
    - Career Volunteer Development Project, LDC, Umatic, Feb 1985
      - Tape 1: Breakfast, Welcome, Purpose (Box 1070, Folder 18)
      - Financial Development (Box 1070, Folder 19)
      - Strategic Planning (Box 1071, Folder 1)
      - Volunteer/Staff Relationships (Box 1071, Folder 2)
      - Tape III, Participants Survey (Box 1071, Folder 3)
      - YWCA Mission (Box 1071, Folder 4)
    - Career Volunteer Development Project, edited copy 12601, Umatic, 15 Mar 1985 (Box 1071, Folder 5)
    - Career Volunteer Development Project, copy 12600, Umatic (Box 1071, Folder 6)
    - National Student Assembly, Umatic, 18-20 Mar 1985
      - Gwen Baker and Sally Ride, 18 Mar (Box 1071, Folder 7)
      - Global Awareness Workshop (2 tapes), 20 Mar (Box 1071, Folder 8-9)
      - El Salvador Refugee, 20 Mar 1985 (Box 1071, Folder 10)
    - National Teen Assembly, Umatic, 18-20 Mar 1985
      - Sally Ride, UCA 20s, 18 Mar (Box 1071, Folder 11)
      - Sally Ride, tape 1 and tape 2, UCA 60, 18 Mar (Box 1071, Folder 12-13)
      - Workshops, 19 Mar (Box 1071, Folder 14)
      - International Delegates (2 of 3 tapes), 19 Mar (Box 1071, Folder 15-16)
      - International Delegates (3 of 3 tapes), 19 Mar (Box 1072, Folder 1)
      - Teen Speeches and Commercials (2 tapes), 19 Mar (Box 1072, Folder 2-3)
    - National Student Assembly and National Teen Assembly: Breakfast Sessions, 19 Mar (Box 1072, Folder 4)
    - National Teen Assembly: A.M. Sessions (2 tapes), 20 Mar 1985 (Box 1072, Folder 5-6)
    - 30th National Convention, San Jose, CA, 21-25 Mar 1985, Umatic
      - Edited Master, UCA 60, [see also box 1070] (Box 1072, Folder 7)
      - Thursday, 21 Mar
        - Opening, Umatic UCA 60 and UCA 20s (Box 1072, Folder 8-9)
        - Registration and Opening Crowd, UCA 20s (Box 1072, Folder 10)
        - Opening Plenary, UCA 60
          - Tape 2: Jewel Graham and Gwen Baker part 1 (Box 1072, Folder 11)
          - Tape 3: Gwen Baker part 2 (Box 1072, Folder 12)
          - Tape 4: opening plenary (Box 1072, Folder 13)
      - Friday, 22 Mar
        - A.M. Plenary
          - Proceedings, UCA 60 (1-2 of 3 tapes) (Box 1072, Folder 14-15)
          - Proceedings, UCA 60 (3 of 3 tapes) (Box 1073, Folder 1)
          - Speaker: Sarah Weddington
            - UCA 20s (Box 1073, Folder 2)
            - Raw footage, UCA 60 (2 tapes) (Box 1073, Folder 3-4)
        - Evening Plenary
          - Proceedings, UCA 60 (3 tapes) (Box 1073, Folder 5-7)
          - Proceedings, crowd shots, candlelight service, UCA 20s (3 tapes) (Box 1073, Folder 8-10)
      - Saturday, 23 Mar
        - Morning Plenary, UCA 60 (2 tapes, numbered 2 and 3) (Box 1073, Folder 11-12)
        - Afternoon Plenary, UCA 60 (3 tapes, numbered 4-6) (Box 1073, Folder 13-15)
        - World Night, UCA 60 (2 tapes, numbered I and II) (Box 1074, Folder 1-2)
        - Gospel Choir, UCA 20s (Box 1074, Folder 3)
        - Polynesian Dancers, UCA 20s (2 tapes) (Box 1074, Folder 4-5)
      - Sunday, 24 Mar
        - Afternoon Plenary, UCA 60 (4 tapes, numbered 1-4) (Box 1074, Folder 6-9)
        - Evening Plenary, UCA 60 (4 tapes, numbered 5-8) (Box 1074, Folder 10-13)
      - Monday, 25 Mar
        - Closing Plenary: Racial Justice, UCA 60 (1 and 2 of 4 tapes, numbered 1-3 and 0) (Box 1074, Folder 14-15)
        - Closing Plenary: Racial Justice, UCA 60 (3 and 0 of 4 tapes, numbered 1-3 and 0) (Box 1075, Folder 1-2)
      - "Photo Edit," UCA 20s and VHS (Box 1075, Folder 3-4)
      - "Review of the 30th National Convention, UCA 20s (Box 1075, Folder 5)
    - United Nations Decade for Women, World Women's Conference, Nairobi, Kenya, UCA 20s, Jun [Jul?] 1985 (Box 1075, Folder 6)
    - Interim Executives Role Play, UCA 60, Nov 1985 (Box 1075, Folder 7)
    - Dee Ann Character, Interview re Volunteer Leadership, UCA 30, 17 Nov 1985 (Box 1075, Folder 8)
    - YWCA/National Women's Education Fund, Model Political Campaign training at YWCA of Chicago
      - "Color Bars," UCA 60, 22 Nov 1985 (Box 1075, Folder 9)
      - "Women Candidates," UCA 60, 23 Nov 1985 (Box 1075, Folder 10)
    - Gwen Baker on the Today show, VHS (poor quality), 1986 (Box 1075, Folder 11)